Hello, I'm Sifu Mallon with the Clearwater Kung Fu Center.
This is my assistant, Melissa, and this is women's self defense.
This self defense tactic is going against the hold.
This is called front head hold so meaning I've got her head in a lock in front of the body.
So what she is going to do is the first thing she is going to do is she is going to neutralize this.
She is going to use the free hand and she is going to grab and pull down on my forearm so I can't lift and get my arch and choke her this way.
Now as she does this she steps back, getting a nice base and now she is going to fire two, one, two, fast groin strikes, then she is going to open her hand and do what is called the wedge strike.
A wedge strike is where you are using the inside web or the wedge of your hand this way.
She is going to straight up this way, push and lift, that way.
Again, so I come forward, I attack this way, grabbing her head.
She neutralizes by pulling the inside hand down.
Okay, she steps back, she groin strikes, one, two, lift, punch.
Now this push, this wedge push as it is coming up is going to come from here and it is going to be more of not like a touch and shove but more like a jab, quick strike.
This is how we do women's self defense.